Alan K. Campbell Papers
Alan K. Campbell Papers
1967-1998
Campbell, Alan K., 1923-1998
21.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, incoming and outgoing carbons; writings, including articles, a book review, transcripts of Campbell’s testimony before various Congressional committees, and speeches (1969-1980); and memorabilia including appointment calendars, clippings, photographs and printed material relating to events at Syracuse University’s Maxwell School, the Civil Service Commission, and the Office of Personnel Management. Correspondence with Jimmy Carter, National Academy of Public Administration, National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, Donna Shalala, and others. Material relating to the Civil Service Reform Act.
150143
Biographical History
American educator, university administrator, and Carter Administration official; b.1923. Campbell served as chairman of the U.S. Civil Service Commission and director of the U.S. Office of Personnel Management.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1967 to 1980, the Alan K. Campbell Papers comprises biographical material, correspondence, writings, and memorabilia of the American educator and Carter Administration official (b. 1923). Covering primarily his years as chairman of the U.S. Civil Service Commission and Director of the U.S. Office of Personnel Management, the collection offers a glimpse of the day-to-day operations of these departments and of Campbell's role in the campaign for civil service reform.
Biographical material (Box 1) consists of documentation prepared by Campbell for his confirmation hearings.
Arranged alphabetically, Correspondence (Boxes 1-16) includes both incoming letters and outgoing carbons which primarily document Campbell's role in the Carter Administration. Notable among the correspondents are: Jimmy Carter, Lloyd Bentsen, Hubert Humphrey, Lady Bird Johnson, George McGovern, Walter Mondale, and Donna Shalala.
A New York Times book review, articles written for a variety of publications, transcripts of Campbell's testimony before various Congressional committees, and his speeches from 1969 through 1980 constitute Writings (Boxes 17-20).
Memorabilia (Boxes 21-34) encompasses appointment calendars (1978-1980); videotapes of the 1998 Campbell Institute Inaugural Symposium with a memorial tribute to Campbell; clippings relating to the New York State Constitutional Convention, the Civil Service Commission, and the Office of Personnel Management; copies of financial records which were submitted for Campbell's confirmation hearings; photographs and printed material relating to events at Syracuse University's Maxwell School, the Civil Service Commission, and the Office of Personnel Management; publications of the Comptroller General's Office, and a few other government and private agencies; press releases (1969-1980); and various personal mementos.
Civil Service Reform Act material (Boxes 35-38) represents a separate set of Campbell's research material received in 2008 and not integrated into the main collection. This material is related almost exclusively to the Civil Service Reform Act and consists of articles and clippings, CSRA oral history material (including a detailed chronology on index cards and transcripts of numerous interviews), and correspondence with (among others) the White House and other government officials.
Related Material
See also the Inter-University Case Program Records.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Campbell, Alan K.; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Shalala, Donna E.; National Academy of Public Administration.; National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration.; Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs.; United States. Office of Personnel Management.; United States Civil Service Commission.; Civil service -- United States.; Civil service -- Personnel management.; Civil service -- Study and teaching.; Civil service ethics -- United States.; Civil service reform -- United States.; Educators -- United States.; Public administration literature.; United States -- Officials and employees -- Selection and appointment.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1977-1981.; Appointment books.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Speeches (documents); Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alan K. Campbell, 1994
Inventory
- Biographical Material
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - A (misc), 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Academy for Contemporary Problems, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - American Consortium for International Public Administration (Box 2)
  - American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - American Productivity Center (Box 2)
  - American Society for Public Administration (Box 2)
  - B (misc), 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Bentsen, Lloyd (Box 3)
  - C (misc), 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 5)
  - Carter, Jimmy (Box 5)
  - Center for Municipal and Metropolitan Research (Box 5)
  - Cleveland Conference, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Committee for Economic Development (Box 5)
  - Cosmos Club (Box 5)
  - D (misc), 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Daedulus (Box 6)
  - District of Columbia Citizens for Better Public Education (Box 6)
  - Ditchley Foundation (Box 6)
  - Domestic Council (Box 6)
  - E (misc), 1 folder (Box 6)
  - F (misc), 1 folder (Box 7)
  - G (misc), 1 folder (Box 7)
  - H (misc), 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Hanley, James M. (Box 7)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Box 7)
  - I (misc), 1 folder (Box 8)
  - J (misc), 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Lady Bird (Box 8)
  - K (misc), 1 folder (Box 8)
  - L (misc), 1 folder (Box 9)
  - M (misc), 3 folders (Box 9)
  - McGovern, George (Box 9)
  - Mondale, Walter (Box 9)
  - Media contacts (Box 9)
  - N-O (misc), 1 folder (Box 10)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - National Association of State and Local Government (Box 11)
  - National Governors Conference (Box 11)
  - National Municipal League (Box 11)
  - New York State Joint Legislative Committee to Revise and Simplify the Education Law, August 1969 (Box 12)
  - P (misc), 1 folder (Box 12)
  - President's Management Intern Program, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Q (misc), 1 folder (Box 13)
  - R (misc), 3 folders (Box 13)
  - S (misc), 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Shalala, Donna (Box 14)
  - State, community resource development leaders (Box 14)
  - Syracuse University, Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public affairs (Box 14)
  - T (misc), 1 folder (Box 15)
  - Texas Southern University (Box 15)
  - U-V (misc), 1 folder (Box 15)
  - United States Civil Service Commission (Box 15)
  - United States Civil service Commission Research Task Force (Box 15)
  - United States Department of Housing and Development (Box 15)
  - W (misc), 2 folders (Box 16)
  - White House (Box 16)
  - Y-Z (misc), 1 folder (Box 16)
  - Unidentified (1 folder) (Box 16)
- Writings
  - Articles A-Z, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Book review (Box 18)
  - Congressional testimony, 1977-1980; 7 folders (Box 18)
  - Speeches
    - 1969-1978, 19 folders (Box 19)
    - 1979-1980, 13 folders (Box 20)
- Memorabilia
  - Calendars, 1978-1980; 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Campbell Institute Inaugural Symposium, 1998; videotapes, photographs, memorial tribute to Campbell (Box 38)
  - Clippings
    - 1967-1978, 10 folders (Box 22)
    - 1979-1980, 10 folders (Box 23)
  - Financial records, 1973-1980; 8 folders (Box 24)
  - Photographs
    See also Campbell Institute Inaugural Symposium
    - 1969-1978, 12 folders (Box 25)
    - 1979-1980, undated, 9 folders (Box 26)
  - Press releases, 1969-1980; 17 folders (Box 27)
  - Printed material
    - Government publications
      - U.S. Civil Service Commission and U.S. Office of Personnel Management (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous (continued) (Box 30)
    - Syracuse University Maxwell School publications (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Telephone logs, 1977-1980; 4 folders (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
- Civil Service Reform Act material
  - Articles and transcripts
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35)
  - Civil Service Reform Act Oral History
    - Alan Campbell and Nancy Dalton interview transcripts, 2 Oct 1980 (Box 35)
    - Campbell interviews (from Jeff Jacobs), 21 Nov 1979 (Box 35)
    - Chronology, 1977-1978 (Box 35)
    - Interviews, A-Z, transcripts; 4 folders (Box 36)
    - Kym Davis and Tony Ingrassia oral interview, 1 Sep 1980; 2 audiocassette tapes (Box 38)
  - Correspondence
    - Press, reporters, 1977-1980 (Box 37)
    - White House
      - General, 1977-1980; 4 folders (Box 37)
      - Memoranda to President and other government officials, 1977-1980; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-1979 (Box 37)